Bosun Adepoju

Email: adepojuolatunbosun@gmail.com - GitHub: aithub.com/adepojubosun - Phone: (716) 431- 0697

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/bosun-adepoiu

Summary

An ambitious and analytical individual with experience in software development and data analysis spanning multiple industries. An experienced team player with a passion for problem-solving and applying acquired skills towards the solution of such problems.

Skills

Languages	Java, Python, C#, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML5/CSS, SQL, Scala
Frameworks	Java Spring, .NET 5, React, Angular, Flask, JQuery, Nodejs, Spark
Tools/Services	GIT, JIRA, AWS, Azure, Docker, Vagrant, SSMS, EF, Spring Data JPA, AVRO, Kubernetes, Apigee, Splunk, Databricks, Azure & AWS Data Lake
Data Platforms	SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, CouchDB, Hadoop, Kafka, RabbitMQ, ActiveMQ, Teradata, CosmosDB
Competencies	Software Architecture, TDD, Big Data, Algorithms & Data Structures, Back End & Front End Development, API Development, Information Security, Cloud Development, Design Patterns, CI/CD

Experience

T-Mobile US, Atlanta, GA

Software Engineer (June 2020 – Present)

- Leading the implementation of an internally deployed web application for human resources & employee management for employee assessment and career growth.
- Deployed and managed multiple services in Amazon EKS Kubernetes clusters using T-mobile's deployment interface (Conduktor).
- Built a user-interface to help internal users create sql server data job process creation using react & redux, and python flask, also deployed on Amazon EC2 instances.
- Built an Oauth2-based authentication & authorization as a microservice, interfacing with active directory (LDAPS), Redis cache, and Microsoft SQL server for role-based access control (RBAC).
- Built a tool for creating JSON-based configuration files by creating a Python script that automatically pulls schema information for multiple relational databases.
- Built multiple APIs for exposing requested data points across multiple departments.
- Designed, architected, and developed a new data pipeline for streaming data from Apache Kafka into multiple relational and nonrelational data platforms using Java Spring Boot and Spring Data.
- Built and managed databricks notebooks for automating ETL processes within multiple data platforms like PostgreSQL, Cosmos DB, SQL Server, and Teradata using Scala running on an Azure Databricks cluster.
- Serving as the primary mentor for interns and helping guide them through productivity, change, learning, and development.

Circuit Clinical, Buffalo, NY

Software Engineer

(September 2018 – June 2020)

- A core member of the team involved in the development of a patient-centric clinical trial platform.
- Facilitated the development and architecture of complex relational database models, relationships, and stored procedures for data processes supporting all projects in SQL Server, PostgreSQL, and NoSQL databases.
- Primarily responsible for a front-end redesign of a clinical trial web platform including the development of features and APIs using .NET Core, React, and other tools.
- Implemented an automatic fuzzy matching algorithm that increased data transformation efficiency to over 80%.
- Developed an optimized autocomplete algorithm that is used throughout the platform.
- Developed a publicly available web rating widget that occasionally pulls information from a secure API living on the platform.
- Designed and developed a Covid-19 response web application to help automate the recording and dissemination of coronavirus tests for employees at different organizations.
- Developed a coronavirus research trial tracking web platform to automate patient recruitment at research centers across the United States and Canada.

Avalonix Group Inc., Amherst, NY

Software Developer

(September 2017 – June 2018)

- Built, tested, and deployed on Azure PaaS, an application that manages customer data, product inventory, sales data, and automates product shipment processes.
- Integrated system with Magento, UPS, and PayPal APIs for customer/product inventory, shipping, and payment management respectively.

Built an interface with ActiveX to enable automatic printing of shipping labels by Zebra printer.

Open Learning Exchange, Cambridge, MA

Software Developer Intern (remote) (January 2018 – May 2018)

- Participated in the development of a cloud-based educational system hosted on Raspberry Pi for children without access to the internet.
- Supported both front-end and back-end code development using Angularjs, CouchDB, Docker, and Vagrant.
- Worked remotely and actively updated codebase for review while effectively communicating with designers and product managers.
- Assisted in the migration of the PLANET App from CouchDB to the PouchDB NoSQL database system to support the PWA.

Appiculate, Lagos, Nigeria

Software Developer Intern (February 2015 – November 2015)

AWOOF Rewards App

• Developed and managed a Java Spring-based wallet socket system as a microservice for the Awoof Mobile Application. The microservice integrates with the rewards platform and manages wallet transactions.

Projects

RUNMED Hospital Management System - Redeemer's University

Role:

Development Lead

Tools

JavaScript, Nodejs, MongoDB, HTML/CSS, ExpressJS, D3.js, JQuery

Details:

A web-based system hosted on an internal university network providing seamless communication within the school clinical system. The system
encompasses multiple areas of the clinic including EHR, finance, administrative, legal, and compliance departments. The system provides
integrated solutions like data access/storage and exchange for services involving the pharmacy, inpatient/outpatient management, billing,
laboratory, appointment scheduling, and ward management.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

MSc. Computer Science, exp. 2022

D'Youville College, Buffalo, NY

BSc. Health Analytics, 2019

Redeemer's University, Osun, Nigeria

BSc. Computer Science, 2015 (transfer) (incomplete)